Edwin Way Teale Papers 1981.0009
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
- Series I: Writings, undated, 1799-1991
  - Subseries D: Published Writings, undated, 1923-1980
    - "Observations of the Migration of the Monarch..." research material, notes, manuscript drafts, correspondence for the Bulletin of the Brooklyn Entomological Society, 1944 December (Box 71:, Folder 2319)
    - "Travels on a Leaf" research material, notes, manuscript drafts for Nature Magazine, 1945 February (Box 71:, Folder 2320)
    - "DDT- Boon of Menace" research material, notes, manuscript, correspondence for Nature Magazine, 1945 March (Box 71:, Folder 2321)
    - "Ludlow Griscom" research material, notes, manuscript drafts, correspondence for Audubon Magazine, 1945 November (Box 72:, Folder 2322)
    - "Typhoid Mary- With Wings" notes, manuscript drafts, correspondence for Coronet, wrote: 1945 November 20 (Box 72:, Folder 2323)
    - "World of a Wild Bee" notes, manuscript for Nature Magazine, 1945 November (Box 72:, Folder 2324)
    - "Arthur Cleveland Bent" research, notes, manuscript drafts, correspondence for Audubon Magazine, 1946 January (Box 72:, Folder 2325)
    - "The World's Most Interesting Animals" notes, manuscript drafts, correspondence for Seventeen, 1946 (Box 72:, Folder 2326)
    - "Insect Trapper" notes, manuscript for Fauna Magazine, 1946 September (Box 72:, Folder 2327)
    - Nature in Action (Series): notes, 1946 (Box 72:, Folder 2328)
    - Nature in Action: clippings, research material, 1946 (Box 72:, Folder 2329)
    - Nature in Action: research & notes, 1946 (Box 72:, Folder 2330)
    - Nature in Action: short manuscripts, correspondence, 1946 (Box 72:, Folder 2331)
    - Nature in Action: "Without Benefit of Brains" notes, drafts, 1946 (Box 72:, Folder 2332)
    - Nature in Action: "Hawkways" manuscript, 1946 (Box 72:, Folder 2333)
    - Nature in Action: "The Humor of the Crow", "A Crow Outwits A Falcon", "Cunning of the Crow" manuscript, 1946 (Box 72:, Folder 2334)
    - Nature in Action: "Inside-Out Stomachs" manuscript, 1946 (Box 72:, Folder 2335)
    - Nature in Action: "The Mouse Man" manuscript, editorial copy, 1946 (Box 72:, Folder 2336)
    - Nature in Action: "Nature Can Teach You Courage" notes, research, manuscript, 1946 (Box 72:, Folder 2337)
    - Nature in Action: "The Mysterious Swift" manuscript, 1946 (Box 72:, Folder 2338)
    - Nature in Action: "Love Songs" & "The Song of Woodcock" proofs, manuscript, 1946 February 20 (Box 72:, Folder 2339)
    - Nature in Action: "Bird With a Sense of Humor", "The Other Side of the Bluejay", "The Backyard Bluejay", proofs, research, notes & manuscript, 1946 (Box 72:, Folder 2340)
    - Nature in Action: "Flower-in-a-Hurry" notes, manuscripts, separation sheet, correspondence, 1946 March 6 (Box 72:, Folder 2341)
    - Nature in Action: "Traveler's Return" notes, manuscript, proof, correspondence, 1946 May 15 (Box 72:, Folder 2342)
    - Nature in Action: "Whisper Songs" notes, print of article, correspondence, 1946 July 1 (Box 72:, Folder 2343)
    - Nature in Action: "The Friendly Pigeon", research, notes, manuscript drafts, print of article, 1946 July 29 (Box 72:, Folder 2344)
    - Nature in Action: "Wild Weather Prophets" research, notes, article, correspondence, 1946 September 26 (Box 72:, Folder 2345)
    - Nature in Action: "Weeds of the Air" research, notes, print of article, separation sheet for photos, 1946 October 7 (Box 72:, Folder 2346)
    - Nature in Action: "The Robin and the Ant" notes, prints of article, correspondence, 1946 October 21 (Box 72:, Folder 2347)
    - Nature in Action: "Adventure Lies Under a Board" research, notes, manuscript, proof, 1946 November 19 (Box 72:, Folder 2348)
    - "Eyes in the Dark", "Worlds Most Valuable Animal", "How Many Leaves on a Tree?", "They Live Without Eating", "The Language Of the Animals", "When Animals Seek Human Aid", "A Talking Brown Thrasher" notes, manuscripts, correspondence, articles for the Ladies Home Journal, 1947 January - December (Box 73:, Folder 2349)
    - "W. H. Hudson's Lost Years" notes, research, manuscript drafts, correspondence, copies of article & proof for the Saturday Review, 1947 April 12 (Box 73:, Folder 2350)
    - "Names That Nobody Knows" research, notes, draft for New York Times Magazine, 1947 July 6 (Box 73:, Folder 2351)
    - "Audubon's Insects" notes, manuscript, correspondence for Audubon Magazine, 1947 November (Box 73:, Folder 2352)
    - "Catching Up With Cruickshank" notes, manuscript for Audubon Magazine, 1947 November (Box 73:, Folder 2353)
    - ----- (Box 73:, Folder 2354)
    - "Scourge of the Monarch", "Turret Eyes", "Pioneer Potter", "Butterfly Botanist" notes & manuscripts for Natural History Magazine, 1948 September - November (Box 73:, Folder 2355)
    - "Birding By Ear; Clarence Hawkes" notes, rough draft, manuscript for Audubon and later the Blinded Veterans Association, 1948 November/1949 June (Box 73:, Folder 2356)
    - "The Ants' Camels" notes, manuscript for Natural History Magazine, 1948 November (Box 73:, Folder 2357)
    - "Flora of the Frost" notes, complete drafts 1 and 2 for the Christian Science Monitor, 1948 December (Box 73:, Folder 2358)
    - "Wildlife in Focus- The Cruickshanks" research, notes, manuscript, correspondence for the Christian Science Monitor, 1948 December (Box 73:, Folder 2359)
    - "Nature Photography, Fifty Years of Progress" research material for Audubon Magazine, 1949 (Box 73:, Folder 2360)
    - "Nature Photography, Fifty Years of Progress" notes for Audubon Magazine, 1949 (Box 73:, Folder 2361)
    - "Nature Photography, Fifty Years of Progress" manuscript drafts, review, correspondence for Audubon Magazine, 1949 (Box 73:, Folder 2362)
    - "The Hell Raisin' Beaver" notes & reference articles for Collier's Magazine, 1949 February (Box 73:, Folder 2363)
    - "The Hell Raisin' Beaver" manuscript for Collier's Magazine, 1949 February (Box 73:, Folder 2364)
    - "The Incredible Ant" research material, notes, manuscript drafts, correspondence for Coronet, 1949 June (Box 73:, Folder 2365)
    - "Fish-Fly" notes, manuscript for Natural History Magazine, 1949 June (Box 74:, Folder 2366)
    - "The Strength of the Cattail" notes, manuscript drafts for Natural History Magazine, 1949 November (Box 74:, Folder 2367)
    - "Insect Travelers" manuscript, correspondence for the Book of Knowledge Annual, 1950 (Box 74:, Folder 2368)
    - "The Jacques" notes, manuscript drafts, correspondence for Audubon Magazine, 1950 January (Box 74:, Folder 2369)
    - "Close-ups of Insects" notes, manuscript, correspondence for U.S. Camera, 1950 April (Box 74:, Folder 2370)
    - "The Bird That Baffled a Continent" research, notes, manuscript drafts, correspondence for Natural History Magazine, 1950 April (Box 74:, Folder 2371)
    - "There's a Zoo in Your Yard" notes, manuscript, correspondence for Friend's Magazine, 1950 May (Box 74:, Folder 2372)
    - "Thoreau's Walden" research material, notes for Outdoor Illustrated, 1950 September (Box 74:, Folder 2373)
    - "Insect Allies" research, notes, manuscript for New York Times, 1950 July 30 (Box 74:, Folder 2374)
    - "Fabre: The Explorer Who Stayed at Home" notes, manuscript drafts, correspondence for Coronet, 1951 February (Box 74:, Folder 2375)
    - "The Riddle of the Marching Mice" notes, manuscript, correspondence for Coronet, 1951 April (Box 74:, Folder 2376)
    - "Galleries Aloft" notes, separation sheet for photos for Natural History Magazine, 1951 May (Box 74:, Folder 2377)
    - "The Praying Mantis- Friend of Man" research, notes, manuscript drafts, correspondence for Coronet, 1951 July (Box 74:, Folder 2378)
    - Insect Series: notes, manuscript, correspondence for Coronet, 1951 (Box 74:, Folder 2379)
    - "Wendel P. Smith- Green Mountain Naturalist" research, notes, manuscript drafts, correspondence for Audubon Magazine, 1951 September (Box 74:, Folder 2380)
    - "The Most Amazing Insect" research, notes, correspondence for Coronet, 1951 September (Box 74:, Folder 2381)
    - "Skyscrapers, Scaup, Skimmers & Skunks" research material, notes, manuscript drafts, correspondence for New York Times, 1951 December 16 (Box 74:, Folder 2382)
    - "Oddities of the Insect World" research, notes, manuscript, correspondence for U.S. Department of Agriculture Yearbook, 1952 (Box 74:, Folder 2383)
    - "John Burroughs Disciple of Nature" notes, manuscript drafts for Coronet, 1952 March (Box 74:, Folder 2384)
    - "Be a Backyard Explorer" notes, manuscript drafts, correspondence for American Magazine, 1952 June (Box 74:, Folder 2385)
    - "Make Friends With Nature" notes, manuscript drafts, correspondence for American Magazine, 1953 (Box 75:, Folder 2386)
    - "Mountains in Flower" notes, manuscript, correspondence for Ford Times, 1953 May (Box 75:, Folder 2387)
    - "Words to Live By: Circle of Seasons Extracts" notes, manuscript drafts, correspondence for This Week Magazine, 1953 December 13 (Box 75:, Folder 2388)
    - "How Do They Move?" research material, notes, manuscript drafts, correspondence for Coronet, 1954 September (Box 75:, Folder 2389)
    - "The Journeying Butterflies" research material, notes, manuscript, correspondence for Audubon Magazine, 1954 September (Box 75:, Folder 2390)
    - "Exploring Your Backyard" Examples of Booklet, 1955 (Box 75:, Folder 2391)
    - "Exploring Your Backyard" Notes, 1955 (Box 75:, Folder 2392)
    - "Exploring Your Backyard" manuscript, undated (Box 75:, Folder 2393)
    - "Exploring Your Backyard" correspondence, invoice, 1955 (Box 75:, Folder 2394)
    - "Exploring Your Backyard" Dummy, 1955 (Box 75:, Folder 2395)
    - "May" notes, manuscript, correspondence for the Saturday Review, 1955 (Box 75:, Folder 2396)
    - "Everglades Boardwalk", "Sponges of the Land", "The Shoestring Fern" research, notes, manuscripts, correspondence for Natural History Magazine, 1955 September (Box 75:, Folder 2397)
    - "Those Phenomenal Insects" notes, manuscript drafts, correspondence for the Pocket Book Magazine, 1955 November (Box 75:, Folder 2398)
    - "The Whooping Crane's Wonderful Comeback" notes, research, manuscript, correspondence for Coronet, 1960 October (Box 75:, Folder 2399)
    - "The American Woods" research, notes, manuscript drafts, correspondence for Holiday Magazine, 1961 (Box 75:, Folder 2400)
    - "Voice of Truth as Heard in the City" notes, manuscript drafts, correspondence, proof for New York Times Magazine, 1957 March 17 (Box 76:, Folder 2401)
    - "Land Forever Wild" research for Audubon Magazine, 1957 May (Box 76:, Folder 2402)
    - "Land Forever Wild" notes for Audubon Magazine, 1957 May (Box 76:, Folder 2403)
    - "Land Forever Wild" manuscript drafts, correspondence for Audubon Magazine, 1957 May (Box 76:, Folder 2404)
    - "Insects Face to Face" manuscript for Audubon Magazine, 1957 September (Box 76:, Folder 2405)
    - "Oldest Migrations" notes, research, manuscript drafts for Natural History Magazine, 1957 September (Box 76:, Folder 2406)
    - "Bird of Freedom" research, notes for Atlantic Monthly, 1957 November (Box 76:, Folder 2407)
    - "Bird of Freedom" manuscript drafts, correspondence for Atlantic Monthly, 1957 November (Box 76:, Folder 2408)
    - "Patches-the-Bird-Watching-Dog" notes, manuscript drafts for Nature Magazine, 1958 January (Box 76:, Folder 2409)
    - "Nature Book for Children" notes, manuscript, correspondence for The New York Times Book Review, 1958 March 15 (Box 76:, Folder 2410)
    - "Bumptious Bird" notes, manuscript, correspondence for New York Times Magazine, 1960 September (Box 76:, Folder 2411)
    - "Valley of the Fossil Insects" manuscript, correspondence for Audubon Magazine, 1960 October (Box 76:, Folder 2412)
    - "The Periodical Cicada" notes, manuscript, correspondence for the Book of Knowledge Annual, 1960 January (Box 76:, Folder 2413)
    - "J. Henri Fabre" schedules, notes, research for Colliers Encyclopedia, 1960 January (Box 76:, Folder 2414)
    - "J. Henri Fabre" manuscripts, correspondence for Colliers Encyclopedia, 1960 January (Box 76:, Folder 2415)
    - "Lost in the Wilderness" notes, manuscript drafts, correspondence for Vermont Life Magazine, 1961 (Box 76:, Folder 2416)
    - "Twelve Way to See More Outdoors" notes, manuscript drafts for Boy's Life, 1961 February (Box 76:, Folder 2417)
    - "The World's First Musicians" notes, manuscript drafts, correspondence for Boy's Life, 1961 April 1 (Box 76:, Folder 2418)
    - -----, undated (Box 76:, Folder 2419)
    - "The Lacewing Fly" manuscript, correspondence for Audubon Magazine, 1962 April (Box 77:, Folder 2420)
    - "The American Woods" manuscript for Holiday Magazine, 1962 June (Box 77:, Folder 2421)
    - "Gulls of the Four Brothers" notes, manuscript, correspondence, proof for Vermont Life Magazine, 1963 November 22 (Box 77:, Folder 2422)
    - "Insect Predators" notes, manuscript, correspondence for Boy's Life, 1963 January 28 (Box 77:, Folder 2423)
    - "Birds of the East" notes & research material, 1963 (Box 77:, Folder 2424)
    - "Birds of the East" introduction & caption material, 1963 (Box 77:, Folder 2425)
    - "Birds of the East" correspondence, 1963 (Box 77:, Folder 2426)
    - "Birds of the West" research material, notes, proof for Woman's Day, 1964-1965 (Box 77:, Folder 2427)
    - "Birds of the West" manuscript captions for Woman's Day, 1964-1965 (Box 77:, Folder 2428)
    - "Birds of the West" manuscript captions for Woman's Day, 1964-1965 (Box 77:, Folder 2429)
    - "Birds of the West" manuscript captions, introduction & correspondence for Woman's Day, 1964-1965 (Box 77:, Folder 2430)
    - "A Day With Samuel Gottscho" notes, manuscript, correspondence for Audubon Magazine, 1965 May (Box 77:, Folder 2431)
    - "Diamondback Hound" manuscript, 1971 February 11 (Box 77:, Folder 2432)
    - "J. Henri Fabre" notes, manuscript drafts, correspondence for Encyclopedia Americana, 1971 June 25 (Box 77:, Folder 2433)
    - "Insect Life: A Boy Scout Handbook" notes for the Boy Scouts of America, undated (Box 77:, Folder 2434)
    - "Big Thicket" research, undated (Box 78:, Folder 2435)
    - "Big Thicket" research, undated (Box 78:, Folder 2436)
    - "Big Thicket" notes, undated (Box 78:, Folder 2437)
    - Big Thicket" manuscript drafts, 1970 (Box 78:, Folder 2438)
    - Big Thicket" edited manuscripts, 1970 December (Box 78:, Folder 2439)
    - Big Thicket" correspondence, 1970-1972 (Box 78:, Folder 2440)
    - Notes for ideas for publications, undated (Box 79:, Folder 2441)
    - "Odd Facts" ideas for articles, ca. 1930 (Box 79:, Folder 2442)
    - Notes- ideas for publications, undated (Box 79:, Folder 2443)
    - Article ideas- research and notes, undated (Box 79:, Folder 2444)
    - Notes for ideas for publications, undated (Box 79:, Folder 2445)
    - To-do lists and book schedules, 1940-1970s (Box 79:, Folder 2446)
    - Film/Movie Related
      - Film Advertisements, undated (Box 80:, Folder 2447)
      - Notes for Near Horizons film, 1943 December (Box 80:, Folder 2448)
      - North With the Spring video- advertising, notes & corresp., 1968-1970 (Box 80:, Folder 2449)
      - Film Script, 1970 Fall (Box 80:, Folder 2550)
    - Book Reviews/Introductions for Other Authors' Books
      - Out of a Clear Sky by Leslie Peltier -manuscript, correspondence & notes by EWT, 1963 (Box 81:, Folder 2551)
      - Starlight Nights by Leslie Peltier -edited copy of manuscript, undated (Box 81:, Folder 2552-2553)
      - Starlight Nights- notes & correspondence, 1964 (Box 81:, Folder 2554)
      - Biography of William T. Davis- notes, manuscript, correspondence, 1948 September 1 (Box 82:, Folder 2555)
      - The Life of a Bee by Maurice Maeterlinck -introduction material: notes, manuscript drafts, correspondence, 1954 March 2 (Box 82:, Folder 2556)
      - Wild America by Roger T. Peterson & James Fisher -galleys, 1955 (Box 82:, Folder 2557)
      - A Field Guide to the Birds by Roger T. Peterson -editing comments, undated (Box 82:, Folder 2558)
      - The Wonderful World of Nature- notes, introduction, correspondence, 1961 May (Box 82:, Folder 2559)
      - Catesby's Birds- introduction drafts, notes, correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 82:, Folder 2560)
      - African Wildlife by Bruce Campbell -notes, manuscript, corresp., 1964 (Box 82:, Folder 2561)
      - Notes & correspondence for review of Wes Lawrence's book, 1970 (Box 82:, Folder 2562)
      - Introduction to Rutherford Platt's book -notes, intro & correspondence, 1971 January 16 (Box 82:, Folder 2563)
      - John Burrough's Slabsides by Elizabeth Burroughs Kelley -draft, galley, ca. 1974 (Box 82:, Folder 2564)
      - Harvest of a Quiet Eye- notes, introduction drafts, correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 82:, Folder 2565)
      - A List of Dublin Birds- introduction, notes, correspondence, 1979 February (Box 82:, Folder 2566)
      - Travels in Alaska by John Muir -notes, manuscript, correspondence, 1979 March 23 (Box 82:, Folder 2567)
      - Plant Marvels in Miniature- manuscript of introduction, undated (Box 82:, Folder 2568)
      - Book Reviews (Organized by book title) A - E, 1940s-1980 (Box 83:, Folder 2569)
      - Book Reviews (Organized by book title) F - M, 1940s-1980 (Box 83:, Folder 2570)
      - Book Reviews (Organized by book title) N - S, 1940s-1980 (Box 83:, Folder 2571)
      - Book Reviews (Organized by book title) T - Z, 1940s-1980 (Box 83:, Folder 2572)
      - Scrapbook of EWT's Book Reviews, 1940-1950 (Box 83:, Folder 2573-2574)
    - Early Writings- Unpublished
      - EWT's early writings, 1904-1905 (Box 84:, Folder 2575)
      - EWT's early writings, ca. 1908-1910 (Box 84:, Folder 2576)
      - EWT's early writings, ca. 1908-1912 (Box 84:, Folder 2577)
      - EWT's early writings and miscellaneous journal pages, ca. 1908-1910 (Box 84:, Folder 2578)
      - EWT's early writings, 1908-1910 (Box 84:, Folder 2579)
      - EWT's early writings: "Adventures From Dan's Diary", "Tales From The Wind", 1908-1910 (Box 84:, Folder 2580)
      - EWT's early writings, ca. 1908-1910 (Box 84:, Folder 2581-2583)
      - EWT's journal, 1908 (Box 84:, Folder 2584)
      - "Tales of Lone Oak" Drafts of chapters 1-9, 1909 (Box 84:, Folder 2585)
      - "Tales of Lone Oak" Drafts of chapters 10-25, 1909 (Box 84:, Folder 2586)
      - "Lone Oak Cat Stories", ca. 1909-1912 (Box 84:, Folder 2587)
      - "Lone Oak Cat Stories", ca. 1909-1912 (Box 85:, Folder 2588)
      - EWT's early writing, ca. 1909 (Box 85:, Folder 2589)
      - "White Tip: Story of an Eagle", 1909 (Box 85:, Folder 2590)
      - "The Engine Cat", ca. 1910 (Box 85:, Folder 2591)
      - "My Aviation Experiences" & "The Inhabitant of Sandy Beach Island", ca. 1910-1914 (Box 85:, Folder 2592)
      - Early Writings, ca. 1910-1914 (Box 85:, Folder 2593)
      - "The Little Brown Fox", 1910 January 3 (Box 85:, Folder 2594)
      - Edwin Way Teale's Composition Book, 1910 (Box 85:, Folder 2595)
      - Edwin Way Teale's Composition Book, ca. 1910-1912 (Box 85:, Folder 2596)
      - Journal of Nature Walks, ca. 1911-1912 (Box 85:, Folder 2597)
      - EWT's early writings, ca. 1911-1916 (Box 85:, Folder 2598)
      - EWT's early writings, ca. 1911-1916 (Box 85:, Folder 2599)
      - "Lone Oak Cat Stories", ca. 1911 (Box 85:, Folder 2600)
      - "Lone Oak Cat Stories", ca. 1911 (Box 85:, Folder 2601)
      - "Lone Oak Cat Stories", ca. 1911 (Box 85:, Folder 2602)
      - "The Motor Twins", ca. 1911 (Box 85:, Folder 2603)
      - Composition book, 1911 (Box 85:, Folder 2604)
      - Composition book, 1911 (Box 86:, Folder 2605)
      - EWT's journal, 1911 (Box 86:, Folder 2606)
      - EWT's journal, 1911 (Box 86:, Folder 2607)
      - Composition book, 1912 (Box 86:, Folder 2608)
      - Composition book, 1912 (Box 86:, Folder 2609)
      - Composition book, 1912 (Box 86:, Folder 2610)
      - Composition book, 1912 December (Box 86:, Folder 2611)
      - Journal, 1913-1914 (Box 86:, Folder 2612)
      - "The Drama" & "Samuel Johnston", 1916 (Box 86:, Folder 2613)
      - "The Golden Gleam", "The Tale of a Frog..." & "The Man With the Artistic Hands", ca. 1916 (Box 86:, Folder 2614)
    - Unpublished Writing
      - EWT's notebook related to writing, 1921-1923 (Box 87:, Folder 2615)
      - EWT's notebook related to writing, 1923-1926 (Box 87:, Folder 2616)
      - EWT's notebook related to writing, 1932-1934 (Box 87:, Folder 2617)
      - "Story Plots", 1910-1920s (Box 88:, Folder 2618)
      - "Story Plots", 1910-1920s (Box 88:, Folder 2619)
      - "Story Plots", 1910-1920s (Box 88:, Folder 2620)
      - EWT's early writings -college, ca. 1918-1922 (Box 88:, Folder 2621)
      - Early writings (unidentified), ca. 1922 (Box 88:, Folder 2622)
      - EWT's class work and notes, 1922 (Box 88:, Folder 2623)
      - Papers from Columbia University, undated, 1924-1925 (Box 88:, Folder 2624)
      - Movie/Play plots, undated, 1926 (Box 88:, Folder 2625)
      - Master's thesis for Columbia University "Jeffries Criticism of the Poetry of Scott and Wordsworth", 1926 Spring (Box 88:, Folder 2626)
      - "Down By the Furnace in February" manuscript, 1928 February 22 (Box 89:, Folder 2627)
      - "He Has a Family of Four Thousand Orchids" notes, manuscript, correspondence, separation sheet, ca. 1931 (Box 89:, Folder 2628)
      - "The Hobby Parade" miscellaneous notes, sketches, 1931-1938 (Box 89:, Folder 2629)
      - "The Two Ardens" manuscript, correspondence, 1936 (Box 89:, Folder 2630)
      - "Incredible Chitin" notes, research, ca.1941 (Box 89:, Folder 2631)
      - "How to Sharpen Your Skates" notes, manuscript, correspondence, ca.1942 (Box 89:, Folder 2632)
      - "Hobert V. Roberts- Night Hunter With a Camera" notes, manuscript drafts, correspondence, 1942 (Box 89:, Folder 2633)
      - "Warden Arthur Eiffler" first draft, notes, correspondence, ca. 1943 (Box 89:, Folder 2634)
      - "Malcolm Rix: His Basement Birds Reproduce Extinct Species" notes, manuscript drafts, correspondence, 1943 March (Box 89:, Folder 2635)
      - "The Web of Life" notes, 1944 June 16 (Box 89:, Folder 2636)
      - "Animal Wisdom" research, notes, 1944 June 16 (Box 89:, Folder 2637)
      - "Insect Mothers" notes, manuscript drafts, correspondence, 1945 (Box 89:, Folder 2638)
      - "Guardian of the Spoonbills" notes, manuscript drafts, corresp., 1945 May 20 (Box 89:, Folder 2639)
      - "Men of Nature" notes, manuscript drafts, 1945 April 30 (Box 89:, Folder 2640)
      - "Night Above the City" or "Eyes in the Dark" notebook, correspondence, 1946 October (Box 89:, Folder 2641)
      - "The Birds Best Friend- Roger Tory Peterson" notes, photo proofs, manuscript drafts, correspondence, 1949 March 4 (Box 89:, Folder 2642)
      - "The Happy Men" notes, manuscript, 1949 September 8 (Box 89:, Folder 2643)
      - "Guidebook to the Insects", 1949 September 13 (Box 89:, Folder 2644)
      - "Insect Flight" research, notes, manuscript, 1950 February 22 (Box 90:, Folder 2645)
      - "Honey Hunters" manuscript, 1950 March 27 (Box 90:, Folder 2646)
      - "A Dog's Life, As He Sees It" research, notes, part of manuscript, correspondence, ca. 1951 (Box 90:, Folder 2647)
      - "The Traveled Seed" notes, manuscript, correspondence, 1954 May 15 (Box 90:, Folder 2648)
      - "America's Most Remarkable Birds" research material, notes, manuscript draft, ca. 1958 (Box 90:, Folder 2649)
      - "1001 Questions Answered About Insects" notes, research, correspondence, ca. 1959 (Box 90:, Folder 2650)
      - "Animal Survival" research and notes, 1965 July 29 (Box 90:, Folder 2651)
      - "Animal Survival" manuscript drafts, correspondence, 1965 July 29 (Box 90:, Folder 2652)
      - Public Speaking articles and notes, undated (Box 90:, Folder 2653)
      - "The Fable of the Flower and the Mountain" manuscript, undated (Box 90:, Folder 2654)